<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anastasios Skarlatidis</title>
    <link>https://anskarl.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anastasios Skarlatidis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 08:16:40 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anskarl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Druid (part 1): A Scalable Timeseries OLAP Database System</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/post/2019/druid-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 08:16:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/post/2019/druid-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Online analytical processing (OLAP) systems are commonly used in many Business Intelligence, Analytics and Data Science applications. According to Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;OLAP is an approach to answer multi-dimensional analytical queries swiftly in computing&amp;rdquo;.
Compared to traditional relational database systems, the main difference is that the data in an OLAP system is being stored in a pre-aggregated and multi-dimensional form. The main benefit of storing data in such form, is that it is optimized for ad-hoc complex aggregations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Event Calculus for Event Recognition</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/tocl15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 23:07:22 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/tocl15/</guid>
      <description>Anastasios Skarlatidis1,2, Georgios Paliouras1, Alexander Artikis3,1 and George A. Vouros2
1Institute of Informatics and Telecommunications, NCSR &amp;ldquo;Demokritos&amp;rdquo; 2Department of Digital Systems, University of Piraeus 3Department of Maritime Studies, University of Piraeus
 Abstract
Symbolic event recognition systems have been successfully applied to a variety of application domains, extracting useful information in the form of events, allowing experts or other systems to monitor and respond when significant events are recognised. In a typical event recognition application, however, these systems often have to deal with a significant amount of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Probabilistic Logic Programming Event Calculus</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/tplp15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 22:42:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/tplp15/</guid>
      <description>Anastasios Skarlatidis1,2, Alexander Artikis1, Jason Filippou1,3 and Georgios Paliouras1
1Institute of Informatics and Telecommunications, NCSR &amp;ldquo;Demokritos&amp;rdquo; 2Department of Digital Systems, University of Piraeus 3University of Maryland, USA 
 Abstract:
We present a system for recognising human activity given a symbolic representation of video content. The input of our system is a set of time-stamped short-term activities (STA) detected on video frames. The output is a set of recognised long-term activities (LTA), which are pre-defined temporal combinations of STA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Event Calculus based on Markov Logic Networks</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/rml11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 22:06:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/rml11/</guid>
      <description>Anastasios Skarlatidis1,2, Georgios Paliouras1, George A. Vouros2, Alexander Artikis1
1Institute of Informatics and Telecommunications, NCSR &amp;ldquo;Demokritos&amp;rdquo; 2Department of Digital Systems, University of Piraeus
 Abstract
In this paper, we address the issue of uncertainty in event recognition by extending the Event Calculus with probabilistic reasoning. Markov Logic Networks are a natural candidate for our logic-based formalism. However, the temporal semantics of Event Calculus introduce a number of challenges for the proposed model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 20:58:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Most of my publications can also be found at DBLP
 Alevizos E., Skarlatidis A., Artikis A., Paliouras G. Probabilistic Complex Event Recognition: A Survey. ACM Computing Surveys 50(5): 71:1-71:31 (2017) (paper, bibtex)
 Michelioudakis E., Skarlatidis A., Paliouras G. and Artikis A. OSLa: Online Structure Learning using Background Knowledge Axiomatization. European Conference, ECML-PKDD, 2016. (paper, online appendix, bibtex)
 Skarlatidis A., Paliouras G., Artikis A. and Vouros G. Probabilistic Event Calculus for Event Recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://anskarl.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 20:58:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anskarl.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description> Anastasios Skarlatidis ~ Data Scientist/Engineer. PhD in Artificial Intelligence, passionate about Machine Learning, Programming and Open-source.
You can find my open-source projects on GitHub. You can view my profile on LinkedIn. I tweet about Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Software Engineering, OSS, Photography, Music and possibly other stuff @anskarl.
Interests  Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence Data Science Data Engineering Probabilistic Graphical Models Complex Event Processing Evolutionary Algorithms Parallel and Distributed Systems Scala Programming Language  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>